<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Bad POTUS]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Bad POTUS]]></description>
        <link>https://thegrid.ai/badpotus/</link>
        <generator>The Grid</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2017 22:11:54 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://thegrid.ai/badpotus/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2017 22:11:28 GMT</pubDate>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gerald Ford]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/1bdd0ed4-7e8c-4f93-a82e-1d9f811eecc2.png">,<blockquote>&quot;Don&apos;t it always seem to go
That you don&apos;t know what you&apos;ve got &apos;til it&apos;s gone&quot; 
</blockquote>,<p><strong>Gerald Ford</strong> never wanted to be President. In fact, that was the quality that helped him become President. Could Nixon’s affable VP be an antidote to the cynical scheming of Nixon? His pleasant personality and complete lack of ambition was the antithesis of Nixon’s poisonous plotting.</p>,<p>The shadow of Watergate was too long, and too dark to escape though. Particularly because Ford pardoned Nixon. The nation was not ready to forgive the former leader and did not take kindly to Ford doing so. Even though Ford felt he had to draw a line under Watergate, and was probably right.</p>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/946a398a-f799-4bba-8db1-65283717b366.jpg">,<p>In fact Ford did move on, and started to achieve a measure of success. For example, by 1976 the economy had begun to recover from the recession. Most importantly, it’s generally accepted that he did start to restore faith in the office of the Presidency after the crippling damage done by Nixon. However, it was too little, too late; and before Ford really had a chance to build and implement his own program, he had to hand over to Jimmy Carter.</p>,<p>He confided to Al Haig after the election:</p>,<p>“Al, this is a very sad time for me. I never really wanted the job. And it was only in the last year or so that I realised that I could do it. And the tragedy is that when I really wanted it, I lost it.”</p>,<blockquote>&quot;The tragedy is that when I really wanted the job, I lost it.&rdquo;</blockquote>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/badpotus/gerald-ford/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">ecfcdcd1-935d-4844-98d9-63944a6df25d</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2016 14:55:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>test</p>,<p>tes</p>,<p>tes</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/badpotus/test/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">f1b101d4-82a9-4aba-a870-abcd04162e5c</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2017 22:16:58 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This is a Test, Darn It!]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>This is a Test, Darn It!</h1>,<p>And no one should judge a test.</p>,<iframe src="https://the-grid.github.io/ed-userhtml/?g=eJzlVc1u4zYQvucpBiqwP4dI3hQLdB1bgJtdN4HjIFj7UhQ90BQlcU2RAknZ657yIO21L9A3ypPsDKU43jjJeoEeCtQHa_45881weC1MrQS40jQqg4WAylgBA1czDc5vlBjC7c2fC8aXhTWNzo65Ucb24Ycx_nq925u_UpQK6zzTmdTFICHXND46GmRy1YWIvPjsj5mShe5zob2wp1F6BDAoT9IRzNlCiUGCdBC9Tc-U5EuIrsQaPpp1BN4AyzJgYM2aGN85vA0OgQOZDaNqE0KF0KSwLUFkmc5UDFcmHiRI74gvdN34eyFS9hH3LH1DntmupCORkRQD_KbuKo0g2Rpune4i45eSDOSilez6LxrvjY5gxVSD7BYDozmhMowQCRS8et0C6EVVK-bb-hGeecc_hkGW_nsldMekR4ME25xit2fXoyuYzX-9_DDEodgZGFmxQvShsepV6X3dT5L1eh1XbCkaJ0wec1Ml6xrnCudC-6SplWGZS056vXdJ76fkfD69_JDngnvX-zGudQGvTyFH42Mn_8C4J73a0xTW7SAXxocRsRucvSbPb2_-HiSUG-Y4EwrDwMY0FsfcecjZCmnpaepXEm-BsFI46ENbrgv2KRy1rKm9NPquM1HahcOL0moGSftNt-aEQA2KLYQaRiNOyijtIL_H_mHc0UroAm_U1_EeNX2PSZ8zmx1gOmZY8AtW1acwxppNc0j8eSngPbNLmGhZlP5AjwmzNJIT-SCvwAVMnoJI47C0KD1Ts3C15OHST8X2gG9gesEFjApxQAGTBkds3MA17jN2gP2UZaxgjjN7IDqXJJmEVfld4Jwba419DpmpJItD-jrjVrDqa_CexY8SH0vNFCD8Hon9gX_S7xfbZAdBT8YfvwnMNlF8atoLituHM71ijrbgS_4S91zL43py3Mp6d7MlnxhqgjQCZ_kw6rbSJ5eZWPqELauTJC-nZyiJMFRrS4e0x4FmlaAdx5XFf9rMJcMLS6LM8KbCLRYvijN6J4e-lC5uq3G_BaYNIrILfDU__x6H4ikMbTMK8eb25p8UXwZIHwBEW1XhWqVlF4h9vbGUCBm01L5FrliFCFuRkVXeOF5Ktm-m6LZvhFJmTXaBhZbfN8ZoQpNZIPb1fMOCmr772vtTnorfJYuffd26xO1N2kBsB2c7Gi_0wtWn7f_P2zcJQnOwowTz97Q1_x-19b_Stjle2ruGfQGITamR" height="244"></iframe>,<p>OK?</p>,<blockquote>Yes</blockquote>,<p>Working for you?</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://the-grid.github.io/ed-userhtml/?g=eJzlVc1u4zYQvucpBiqwP4dI3hQLdB1bgJtdN4HjIFj7UhQ90BQlcU2RAknZ657yIO21L9A3ypPsDKU43jjJeoEeCtQHa_45881weC1MrQS40jQqg4WAylgBA1czDc5vlBjC7c2fC8aXhTWNzo65Ucb24Ycx_nq925u_UpQK6zzTmdTFICHXND46GmRy1YWIvPjsj5mShe5zob2wp1F6BDAoT9IRzNlCiUGCdBC9Tc-U5EuIrsQaPpp1BN4AyzJgYM2aGN85vA0OgQOZDaNqE0KF0KSwLUFkmc5UDFcmHiRI74gvdN34eyFS9hH3LH1DntmupCORkRQD_KbuKo0g2Rpune4i45eSDOSilez6LxrvjY5gxVSD7BYDozmhMowQCRS8et0C6EVVK-bb-hGeecc_hkGW_nsldMekR4ME25xit2fXoyuYzX-9_DDEodgZGFmxQvShsepV6X3dT5L1eh1XbCkaJ0wec1Ml6xrnCudC-6SplWGZS056vXdJ76fkfD69_JDngnvX-zGudQGvTyFH42Mn_8C4J73a0xTW7SAXxocRsRucvSbPb2_-HiSUG-Y4EwrDwMY0FsfcecjZCmnpaepXEm-BsFI46ENbrgv2KRy1rKm9NPquM1HahcOL0moGSftNt-aEQA2KLYQaRiNOyijtIL_H_mHc0UroAm_U1_EeNX2PSZ8zmx1gOmZY8AtW1acwxppNc0j8eSngPbNLmGhZlP5AjwmzNJIT-SCvwAVMnoJI47C0KD1Ts3C15OHST8X2gG9gesEFjApxQAGTBkds3MA17jN2gP2UZaxgjjN7IDqXJJmEVfld4Jwba419DpmpJItD-jrjVrDqa_CexY8SH0vNFCD8Hon9gX_S7xfbZAdBT8YfvwnMNlF8atoLituHM71ijrbgS_4S91zL43py3Mp6d7MlnxhqgjQCZ_kw6rbSJ5eZWPqELauTJC-nZyiJMFRrS4e0x4FmlaAdx5XFf9rMJcMLS6LM8KbCLRYvijN6J4e-lC5uq3G_BaYNIrILfDU__x6H4ikMbTMK8eb25p8UXwZIHwBEW1XhWqVlF4h9vbGUCBm01L5FrliFCFuRkVXeOF5Ktm-m6LZvhFJmTXaBhZbfN8ZoQpNZIPb1fMOCmr772vtTnorfJYuffd26xO1N2kBsB2c7Gi_0wtWn7f_P2zcJQnOwowTz97Q1_x-19b_Stjle2ruGfQGITamR</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">b06e69d5-6024-4cc3-829d-ac118ace877a</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2017 22:14:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What about the other Presidents?]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/82faf4a1-39ef-4dbd-b999-6015b2aca021.jpg">,<h2><strong>What about the </strong><em><strong>other</strong></em><strong> Presidents?</strong></h2>,<blockquote>&ldquo;Ask not what your country can do for you, ask what you can do for your country&rdquo;</blockquote>,<p>There is so much we can learn from the ‘great’ presidents: “The only thing we have to fear is fear itself” (FDR), “Speak softly and carry a big stick”(Teddy Roosevelt), “You can fool all of the people some of the time, and some of the people all of the time, but you can not fool all of the people all of the time” (Lincoln).</p>,<p>We want heroes. Leaders we can look up to, which help shore up our own identity so we can take pride in our country. But what about the <em>other</em> presidents? The one’s we may not be inclined to be so proud of?</p>,<blockquote>&quot;Hey Hey LBJ, how many kids did you kill today?&quot;</blockquote>,<p>I’ve found it interesting to look at the lives of Presidents who may have left office in disgrace or who clearly had major character faults. Sometimes the lessons that can be learnt from these - the ‘other’ Presidents are at least as valuable as what I’ve learned from the ‘hero’ Presidents. Because, let’s face it there are no such thing as heroes.</p>,<p>One of the things I discovered as I moved from childhood to maturity is that my heroes didn’t exist.</p>,<p>They were real people: I wasn’t into superheroes; but they weren’t the perfect human specimens that I thought they were. For example, there was one woman I really admired as a boy. She had achieved some incredible things. However, when I slipped out of childhood, I noticed that she had also been guilty of a bunch of really bad stuff.</p>,<p>She is still one of my heroes, but she is not the person I envisioned as a child.</p>,<p>So, to answer the question about US Presidents: I would guess you could put any of them in the category of a “bad President” at some point in their administration. Even those universally recognised as heroes now were imperfect in some areas.</p>,<p><em>However, some US Presidents managed to show their flaws more prominently than others, and those are the ones I’m interested in.</em></p>,<p>It’s easy to dismiss a flawed man as bad man, but if he made it to president, then perhaps he did something right. And if there is nothing he did right, there is at least a good story to be told.</p>,<p>So what could I learn from their journey to the white house? And what can me teach me from what he did he achieved the Presidency? Is there anything I can learn from that?</p>,<img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/8ef5d01a89fbe1fa368877ecceaeb9ee6aee30d5.jpg">]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/badpotus/heroes-good-things-we-can-learn-from-bad-presidents/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">b1b4f111-56db-424c-81a5-b3da0f7f37d1</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2016 15:42:45 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No title]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/6ebcf9e5-4885-4bdb-bcf2-4288801e65d2.jpg">,<p>LBJ had a goal to become president and ruthlessly and single-mindedly followed that goal. He adopted and believed in the goal very early.</p>,<p>Lyndon Johnson was 21 years old he just completed an enough credit at is University to be able to become a teacher. With the help of the President of the University, With whom he was close, he manage to get a job at Welhausen School</p>,<p>Lyndon Johnson was 21 years old, he just received enough credit from college to take a teaching position in a small school called… the students in the school were Mexican immigrants. They were treated very badly by the local population, in actual fact most people did not want to see a Mexican school. They believe that the Mexicans were only good for manual labour and that educating them with any given aspirations four things beyond their reach. In fact requirement was so negative towards these Mexican children that there were frequent murders of Mexicans either local population which were unreported, Or which no one was brought to justice for. Into this environment steps Lyndon Johnson, full of enthusiasm teach these children and not only that, to transform their lives.</p>,<p>The children admired the Lynden immensely. But being kids one of them was very good at imitating their teacher. And one day one of the children, Danny Garcia, entertained class with an impression of the tall gangly teacher with an awkward manner. Linda Johnson came in the room I was furious he held onto the boy and it's hard in front of the rest of the class the indicating him. And being disrespectful. He said to the boy quote don't you realise you're marking the future president of the United States" he was only 20 years old and yet he already had a certainty that his destiny was to be president of America. This is Lyndon Johnson LJ. Not only did that self-fulfilling prophecy come true he was the 36th president of United States, But he also did more than any other president before or since to help migrants in the situation that is school children stop is he didn't become president until he was in his 50s. What amazes me about this story is the confidence of the young Lyndon Johnson that would one day lead the most the most powerful nation on the earth.</p>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/cbd324df-423d-4ba9-b984-429e96d7bfc1.jpg">]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/badpotus/lbj-had-a-goal-to-become-president-and-ruthlessly-and-single/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">544df794-e8ea-4fb2-ac3d-44e57e63c7dd</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2016 12:12:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Don’t it Always Seem That Way?]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>Don’t it Always Seem That Way?</h1>,<h3><em>“Don’t it always seem that way</em><br><em>That you don’t know what you’ve got til it’s gone” </em><br><em>Joni Mitchell</em></h3>,<p>Ford did not have an easy time picking up the Republican nomination. In many people’s minds Reagan looked like he had a much more exciting and radical platform. Some felt that the fight against Reagan damaged him in the subsequent election battle with Carter. However, it was probably the battle with Reagan that helped Ford recognise that this was something he really wanted. Sadly, just as he realised he wanted the Presidency, he lost it.</p>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/716602a1-49bb-43c5-b682-7647f28057d4.jpg">,<p>Ford seemed initially to be an antidote to the cynical scheming of Nixon? His pleasant personality and complete lack of ambition was the antithesis of Nixon’s poisonous plotting. "I have not campaigned either for the presidency or the vice presidency" he told the nation in his inaugural address; "I have not sought this enormous responsibility, but I will not shirk it."</p>,<p>However, the shadow of Watergate was too long, and too dark to escape. The real blow to any of Ford’s ambitions to actually win his office was self-inflicted: he pardoned Nixon. The nation was not ready to forgive the former leader and did not take kindly to Ford doing so. It seemed to underline the suspicion that Government was corrupt. Ford felt he had to draw a line under Watergate, but he drew a line through his own reputation.</p>,<p>In fact Ford did move on, and started to achieve a measure of success. For example, by 1976 the economy had begun to recover from the recession. Most importantly, it’s generally accepted that he did start to restore faith in the office of the Presidency after the crippling damage done by Nixon. However, it was too little, too late; and before Ford really had a chance to build and implement his own program, he had to hand over to Jimmy Carter.</p>,<p>He confided to Al Haig after the election:</p>,<p>“Al, this is a very sad time for me. I never really wanted the job. And it was only in the last year or so that I realised that I could do it. And the tragedy is that when I really wanted it, I lost it.”</p>]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/badpotus/dont-it-always-seem-that-way/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">d196782b-968b-46d2-ad09-fe2c9f0163b4</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2016 15:05:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nixon & Clinton]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/228d01cb-aafb-40ed-be1c-f0c178db47c0.jpg">,<h1>Nixon &amp; Clinton</h1>,<p>On a cold Wednesday morning in 1973, John Dean was talking with his boss about how to get hold of hush money. “The Godfather” had been released in cinemas that year, and this conversation was like a scene from that movie.</p>,<p>“You could get a million dollars.” Richard Nixon, Dean’s boss told him, “You could get it in cash. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=i96VS_z8y7g">I know where it could be gotten</a>.”</p>,<p>The exchange became legendary when Nixon’s tapes were released in subsequent years.</p>,<p>Fast forward 20 years to 93 and it was Nixon himself giving a President some advice. Nixon told President Bill Clinton, who had been elected the previous year: “when asking for guidance from people who are more experienced than you, tell them what you plan to do first — and then ask for their reaction.” Advice on asking for advice. In fact, Nixon was a frequent source of advice to Clinton. Nixon proved to be a useful and accurate counsellor to the young President, particularly on the Soviet Union. We may have expected Clinton to turn to fellow Southern Baptist and Democrat Jimmy Carter, but not to Nixon, a Republican, and a scourge of liberals the world over. Even fellow Republican Barry Goldwater described him as “the most dishonest individual I ever met in my life.”</p>,<p>And the thing is: It was good advice! For Bill Clinton a young President with very little foreign policy experience, who was dealing with the on-going collapse of the USSR, it was timely and useful counsel. Clinton got help where he could get it, and knew that Nixon, who had a number of foreign policy successes, was the right man. Ronald Reagan taught Clinton how to do a proper military salute. Nancy Gibbs describes how the two Presidents stood together, in Reagan’s LA office, perfecting Clinton’s salute. For that matter, Clinton also picked up some golf tips from Gerald Ford. Bill Clinton was not too partisan to learn from Republican Presidents, even from Richard Nixon, scourge of liberals the world-over and famous for Watergate. No matter how bad your worst president is, the chances are they did something right Who would you cite as the worst US President? Even if you’ve never been to America, you probably have an opinion on who is a ‘Bad President’. Perhaps Obama is on your list, or any of the presidents mentioned above: Clinton, Carter, Reagan, Ford or Nixon. But no matter how bad your worst president is, the one you love to hate, the chances are they did something right, and there’s something we can learn from them. Which is what this series is all about. Things I have personally learned from looking at the lives of ‘bad’ presidents.</p>,<blockquote>&quot;When seeking advice from people who are more experienced than you,&quot; Nixon urged, &quot;tell them what you plan to do first &mdash; and then ask for their reaction. Don&rsquo;t ask for advice and then ignore it.&quot;</blockquote>,<p> “He was the most dishonest individual I ever met in my life. President Nixon lied to his wife, his family, his friends, longtime colleagues in the US Congress, lifetime members of his own political party, the American people and the world.” from Goldwater, September 1988, by Barry Goldwater and Jack Casserly. The Invisible Bridge: The Fall of Nixon and the Rise of Reagan, August 2015, by Rick Perlstein. In this book and in Nixonland, Rick Perlstein gives a fantastic insight into the times and culture of Nixon’s presidency. This article is intended to be part of a series. The next one is on LBJ.</p>,<img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/1a368e9a7abc0f3e5ef4ed87f0bcfcb80673bce5.jpg" title="Clinton gets advice from Nixon" alt="Picture text">]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/badpotus/good-things-clinton-learned-from-nixon/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">fb940e2a-badf-47fd-b4f2-5df538d6ac92</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2016 17:11:37 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nixon & Clinton]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<img src="https://s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/the-grid-img/p/1a368e9a7abc0f3e5ef4ed87f0bcfcb80673bce5.jpg" title="Nixon &amp; Clinton">]]></description>
            <link>https://thegrid.ai/badpotus/nixon-and-clinton/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">3fd5bccb-9f5f-4e24-87bc-a3ef89995ef6</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2016 11:04:31 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>